# Miguel Manguerra

- migoymanguerra@gmail.com
- 778-977-9021
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/miguelmanguerra/
- 床 https://miguelmanguerra.vercel.app/
- Victoria, Canada

#### 2 Profile

A fifth year computer engineering student expected to graduate in August 2023 with extensive electronics product development experience. In his most recent coop with Starfish Medical, he was exposed to the rigorous product development process necessary in medical applications. By leading a team at Ergonomyx technologies: he developed an IoT office equipment product. Currently, he is working with Salyx Medical to develop their IoT vitals tracker that monitor the health factors of a user.

#### **Education**

#### University of Victoria,

Fifth Year Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Engineering) Sep 2018 - Aug 2023 | Victoria, Canada

## Relevant Skills

- Highly advanced experience in designing Printed Circuit Boards in Altium and KiCAD.
- Accomplished at drawing, understanding, and organizing complex electrical schematics.
- Adept in soldering and troubleshooting electronics with a variety of testing and measurement equipment.
- Rapid problem-solving skills that involve quick thinking, smart research skills, and flexibility to any situation.
- Procured a wide variety of components and PCBs from Digikey, Mouser, JLCPCB and, PCBWay.
- Developed custom firmware for STM32Fo and ESP32 microcontrollers using Eclipse and PlatformIO.
- Proficient in C, C++, CAPL, MATLAB, and Python.
- Extensive experience modelling challenging circuits with LTspice and other SPICE simulators.
- Intermediate experience modelling prototype designs in Solidworks, NX, and Fusion 360.
- An expert at manufacturing products with 3D printing.
- Developed documentation in accordance with the requirements of ISO 13485 and IEC 60601.



# Professional Experience

**Electronics Engineer**, Salyx Medical  $\oslash$ May 2023 - present | Victoria, Canada

- Performing verification testing on an innovative IoT medical device that tracks a user's health vitals.
- Developing a USB-C charging PCB that allows users to safely charge the embedded Lithium Ion battery within each vitals tracker.

**Electrical Engineering Co-op**, Starfish Medical Sep 2022 – Dec 2022 | Victoria, Canada

- Designed and built custom PCBs for a variety of medical devices.
- · Analyzed analog and digital circuits using electronics lab equipment.
- Performed experiments to determine the most optimal path forward to developing a reliable and safe medical device.

# Electronic Prototype Engineering Co-op,

Ergonomyx Technologies 🤣

Sep 2020 - Aug 2021 | Victoria, Canada

- Led a team of four to develop and prototype a universal smart desk controller that can control any type of existing motorized sit stand
- Designed a USB-A charging PCB that could charge a smart phone or an iPad from the power generated by a user's pedaling.

### Product Designer - Software Co-op,

Dometic (formerly SeaStar Solutions) 🔗

Jan 2020 – Apr 2020 | Vancouver, Canada

- Performed system level testing on electronic systems with complex CAN networks.
- Analyzed data recorded on CAN buses using Vector's CANalyzer.

# **♠** Community Involvement

# University of Victoria Environmental **Engineering Club**, Electrical Team Lead *?*

Sep 2021 - Sep 2022 | Victoria, Canada

- Designed a Smart Power Board that monitors and controls four different power lines.
- Led the design of the USV's plethora of electronics, including the Central Controller Board, and its custom built battery pack.

# Projects

Some of Miguel's current projects include a force sensing robotic manipulator arm and an open source programmable DC electronic load. For more information about his projects visit his project portfolio 🤗